University of Arizona Business and Professional Women’s Club Records, 1964-2013
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Business and Professional Women’s 1964-2013
MS 509
University of Arizona Business and Professional Women’s Club
The University of Arizona Business and Professional Women’s Club (UA/BPW) records contains materials relating to the club’s presence at the University of Arizona since its establishment in 1964. The collection is divided into nine series: club history, publications, meeting minutes and agendas, correspondence, scrapbook albums, program materials, awards, ephemera and political material.
7.25 Linear feet.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The University of Arizona Business and Professional Women’s Club (UA/BPW) was organized in 1964 becoming a chapter of the Arizona Federation of Business and Professional Women’s Clubs (BPW/AZ) and the National Federation of Business Women’s Clubs (BPW/USA). At the club’s founding meeting at the University, President Richard Harvill officially recognized UA/BPW at the University of Arizona campus. The University of Arizona Business and Professional Women’s Club became the first BPW club charted at a college campus by the BPW/USA.
UA/BPW members during the 1960’s and 1970’s were a mix of classified staff and faculty but later were mainly women who worked on campus as classified staff employees ranging from business managers, administrative assistants, etc.. The goals of the organization was to provide networking and support for the women on campus, address legislative and social issues affecting women, and provide scholarships for women. In addition to the commitment of their activities on campus, many members were also active members of other clubs and organizations that supported women issues in society.
Over the years, the club brought many successful events, projects and programs to the campus to help reach their goals. Some of their most notable achievements were sponsoring the Bring Your Boss to Lunch fundraiser (1964-1986); sponsoring approximately 6 annual Women in Management Conferences on campus (1960’s-1970’s); sponsoring yearly film shows on women’s issues on campus for faculty, staff, and students (1990); sponsoring a brown bag lunch series on career related topics (1994-1997); lobbying for Senate Bills 1168 and 1291 (1998-1999); and co-sponsoring pay equity events with NOW and Tucson’s Women’s Commission (1994-2004).
Arrangement
This collection is organized into nine series
Series I: Club History 1964-2013
Series II: Publications 1954-2012
Series III: Meeting Minutes and Agendas 1964-2011
Series IV: Correspondence 1964-2011
Series V: Scrapbook Albums 1964-2011
Series VI: Program Material 1964-2005
Series VII: Awards 1970-2012
Series VIII: Ephemera 1964-2009
Series IX: Political Material 1971-2003
Scope and Content Note
The collection (1964-2013), contains materials including meeting minutes and agendas, club history, correspondence, publications, scrapbooks of newspaper clippings related to the clubs members and activities they were involved in and photographs.
Access Terms
University of Arizona. Business and Professional Women’s Club
University of Arizona--History
Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Arizona
Universities and colleges -- Arizona -- Faculty
Clubs--Arizona--Tucson
Women--Arizona
Political Clubs--Societies and Clubs
Tucson--Arizona--United States
Container List
- Series I: Club History 1964-2013
  Contains the club overview, bylaws, membership lists, financial records, officer nominations and reports from past officers.
  - Overview, 1987-2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, 1964-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bylaws, 1996-2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership List, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership List, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Membership List, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership List, 1999-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership List, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Membership List, 2004-2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Training Documents, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Financial Receipts, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Financial, 1964-1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fundraising, 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Officer Nominations, 1991-2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Officer Reports, 1969-1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notes of President Angie Toledo, 2000-2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series II: Publications 1953-2013
  Contains the clubs newsletters, Around Old Main newsletters, The Communicator Newsletter, Pep * Talk newsletter, Arizona Women Magazine, and Arizona Business Woman Magazine.
  - Around Old Main Newsletter, 1965-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pep* Talk, 1969-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Communicator Newsletter, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Club Newsletters, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Club Newsletters, 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Club Newsletters, 2004-2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Woman Magazines, 1953-1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arizona Woman Magazines, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Arizona Woman Magazines, 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Arizona Woman Magazines, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Woman Magazines, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Business Woman Magazines, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Arizona Business Woman Magazines, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Arizona Business Woman Magazines, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Arizona Business Woman Magazines, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Business Woman Magazines, 1997-2004 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Business Woman Magazines, 2005-2008 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Arizona Business Woman Magazines, 2009-2012 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series III: Meeting Minutes and Agendas 1964-2011
  Contains the meeting minutes and agendas from 1964 to 2011.
  - Minutes, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1994-2003 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Agenda’s and sign-in sheets, 1998-2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Agenda’s and sign-in sheets, 2002-2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2004-2011 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Correspondence 1964-2011
  Contains various letters between the club officers, members, etc., in regards to meetings, events, workshops, issues, etc.
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-May 1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, June-Dec. 1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1976-Aug. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1990-June 1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July 1992-Dec. 1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1995-2007 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2008-2011 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Series V: Scrapbook Albums 1964-2011
  Contains photographs and ephemera taken from disbound photo albums and scrapbooks that were put together over the years by the club.
  - Ephemera, 1970-1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ephemera, 1970-1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Photos and Newspaper Clippings, 1962-1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1964-1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1964-1999 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1964-1999 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, 1964-1984 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, 1964-1995 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, 1996-2007 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 2000-2011 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Ephemera, Newspaper clippings, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Series V: Program Materials 1965-2005
  Contains various documents affiliated with club sponsored events and workshops such as the paperwork from the events/workshops, scripts, videos, etc.
  - Bring Your Boss to Lunch, 1965-1981 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bring Your Boss to Lunch, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Orientation, 1997-2001 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Young Careerist, 2002-2005 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Workshops, 1984-2001 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Workshops, 1990-1996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Events, 1983-2005 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Events, 2000-2003 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Workshops, 2002-2005 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Wonder Woman Workshop VHS, 1992 (Box 13)
- Series VII: Awards 1970-2003
  Contains certificates awarded to members of the club, as well as entry forms and reports for trophies.
  - Club Reports/Entries, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Club Entries, 1972-1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Entries and Newspaper Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Certificates and Newspaper Clippings, 1970-1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Certificates and Entries, 1970-2003 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Certificates, 1984-2012 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Entries and Newspaper Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Series VIII: Ephemera 1964-2009
  Contains various flyers, brochures, cards, letters, etc.
  - Ephemera, 1964-1969 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ephemera, 1974-1999 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera, 1999-2009 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ephemera, 1970- 1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Series IX: Political Materials 1971-2003
  Contains documents dealing with the political forums the club attended as well as legislative forums. Senate bills and women’s workplace issues are also found in this series.
  - Forums, Memo’s, Attendance, 1971-1994 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - State Reports and Letters, 1979-2002 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Legislative Forum, 1979-2002 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Senate Bills, Negotiating, 1997-2003 (Box 15, Folder 7)